flarum.org 2019-03-31

# Flarum – Forums Made Simple

Thank you for visiting Flarum. We respect and protect the privacy of our users. This privacy policy tells you how we collect and use information.

## What information do we collect?

We collect information from you when you register on our site and gather data when you participate in the forum by reading, writing and evaluating the content shared here.

When registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your name and email address. You may, however, visit our site without registering. Your email address will be verified by an email containing a unique link. If that link is visited, we know that you control the email address.

When registered and posting, we record the IP address that the post originated from. We also may retain server logs which include the IP address of every request to our server.

## What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalise your experience - your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.
  * To improve our site - we continually strive to improve our site offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * To improve customer service - your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.
  * To send periodic emails - the email address you provide may be used to send you information, notifications that you request about changes to topics or in response to your username, respond to inquiries and/or other requests or questions.

## How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit or access your personal information.

## What is your data retention policy?

We will make a good faith effort to:

  * Retain server logs containing the IP address of all requests to this server for no more than 90 days.
  * Retain the IP addresses associated with registered users and their posts for no more than 5 years.

## Do we use cookies?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your browser (if you allow). These cookies enable the site to recognise your browser and, if you have a registered account, associate it with your registered account. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however, if you do this you may not be able to use all functionality on our site.

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

## Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our site, conducting our business or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies or protect ours or others rights, property or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising or other uses.

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.

By using Flarum, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described in Google’s Privacy Policy and for the purposes set out above. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the opt-out service provided by Google. Be aware that if you disable JavaScript completely you will impact the normal functionality of Flarum.

## Third Party Links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our site. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Our site, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. If this server is in the USA, and you are under the age of 13, per the requirements of COPPA ([Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Children%27s_Online_Privacy_Protection_Act)), do not use this site.

## Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our site and not to information collected offline.

## Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our site privacy policy.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy?

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.

This document is CC-BY-SA. It was last updated on January 21st, 2018. It has been adapted from a document by [Civilized Discourse Construction Kit, Inc.](https://meta.discourse.org/privacy)
